<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<atom:link href="http://dominicwarren.com/rssfeed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<title>Dominic Warren</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/</link>
<description>Walker, reader and UX writer.</description>

<item>
<title>Having your work shared</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/work-shared</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/work-shared</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
	<![CDATA[
	
<p>I initially started my blog articles as an element of my portfolio. UX writing work is really hard to showcase, it certainly is different to visual design. But the articles are a way for me to show my thinking and what I’ve learnt.</p>
<p>However, it’s really nice and encouraging when you see people sharing them. Especially when those people are well-known across the industry or are people you admire.</p>
<p>One person who has shared my article, <a href="http://dominicwarren.com/posts/what-is-ux-writing">What is UX writing?</a>, is <a href="https://twitter.com/jmspool" target="_blank">Jared Spool</a>.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">As <a href="https://twitter.com/dominicwarren1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dominicwarren1</a> explains, you can begin a project by writing a conversation between your design and your user. This exercise helps you determine what content you need in the design.<br><br>We’ll share this great resource with <a href="https://twitter.com/CenterCentre?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CenterCentre</a> students.<a href="https://t.co/eYzee4CjzW">https://t.co/eYzee4CjzW</a></p>&mdash; Jared Spool (@jmspool) <a href="https://twitter.com/jmspool/status/1159090570381418497?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 7, 2019</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>When I saw it, it’s safe to say, I was shocked. To have your work recognised and shared by someone with the influence and reach Spool does is really exciting. It’s also a great sense of validation — that proponents in the industry agree with what I think and write.</p>
<p>It’s also great that he’s shared it a number of times, quoting different parts of the article.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">“One big area of difference between a UX writer and most other writing is how closely we work with designers.<br><br>It doesn’t make any sense to build a service or product and then drop words into it at the very end.”<br><br>— <a href="https://twitter.com/dominicwarren1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dominicwarren1</a><a href="https://t.co/eYzee4CjzW">https://t.co/eYzee4CjzW</a></p>&mdash; Jared Spool (@jmspool) <a href="https://twitter.com/jmspool/status/1175999231309623301?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2019</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">In this article, <a href="https://twitter.com/dominicwarren1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dominicwarren1</a> explains how UX writers and designers benefit from working together from the beginning of a project.<br><br>It doesn’t make sense to build a product, then try to drop content in at the end.<a href="https://t.co/eYzee4CjzW">https://t.co/eYzee4CjzW</a></p>&mdash; Jared Spool (@jmspool) <a href="https://twitter.com/jmspool/status/1165755231830982657?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 25, 2019</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>I was also really surprised when I received an issue of Ten Things, by <a href="https://twitter.com/La_Pope" target="_blank">Lauren Pope</a>. Under Thing 3 I found my own article, <a href="http://dominicwarren.com/posts/accepting-feedback" target="_blank">Don't be precious: accepting edits and feedback</a>, listed.</p>
<p><a href="https://us3.campaign-archive.com/?u=745f6a81d2d1e196c7d473704&id=4dc0429eb9" target="_blank">Lauren Pope’s Ten Things</a></p>
<p>Lauren is someone I’ve admired since I started in the industry. So to see my article listed on her newsletter is a great feeling.</p>
<p>Again, having your work recognised like this is wonderful. It’s one of the reasons I’m keen to share articles I like on <a href="https://twitter.com/dominicwarren1" target="_blank">my Twitter</a>. I might not have as many followers as some, but it’s a way for me to say I really enjoyed the article.</p>
<p>I'd really recommend <a href="https://mailchi.mp/b140ade59ab5/ten-things" target="_blank">signing up to Ten Things</a>. It's always full of interesting articles.</p>
<p>PS you can read an <a href="https://medium.com/everywordmatters/lauren-pope-freelance-c3d1df376649" target="_blank">interview with Lauren at every word matters</a>.</p>

]]>
	</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Healthy naivety</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/healthy-naivety</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/healthy-naivety</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
	<![CDATA[
	
<p>Our job as UX writers is to make complex information as simple and clear as possible. But there are many things that threaten this. Assumed knowledge, biases, internal myths and jargon can all cloud our vocabulary and seep into our writing.</p>
<p>What we think is clear, concise copy can quickly become technical, confusing commands that lack any empathy.</p>
<p>So how do we avoid this? One of the best tools in a UX writer’s toolkit is what I refer to as ‘healthy naivety’.</p>
<h2>What is ‘healthy naivety’?</h2>
<p>I see healthy naivety as an expansion on beginner’s mind. Beginner’s mind, or shoshin, is a term from Zen Buddhism. To have a beginner’s mind is to have an open attitude that lacks any preconceptions. You approach things willing to learn something new and without bringing any biases.</p>
<p>Healthy naivety is a similar attitude. When writing you, of course, need some understanding of what you’re writing about. But keeping yourself a safe distance from <i>everything</i> you need to know can be really beneficial. We need to <a href="/posts/plain-english-isnt-dumbing-down">write in the simplest way possible for many reasons</a>. By having a healthy naivety we can question things where appropriate and also better explain things in plain English.</p>
<h2>Always question</h2>
<p>By not having a complete understanding we’re more aware of things that aren’t clear or don’t make sense. What might make sense to somebody who’s worked on the product for years might actually be really unclear. So you can question and investigate that.</p>
<p>Getting a colleague to explain things by email can lead to overly-formal explanations. They might even copy and paste from a number of different authors, some technical, some not. But by getting people to explain things out loud, in conversation, you often get much better language cues. You can then use these in your writing. This keeps your copy human and allows you to clearly define things for the user.</p>
<h2>Plain and simple writing</h2>
<p>Users don’t sit in the office looking at your product all day. They’re new to it, so it needs to be understandable for them.</p>
<p>Healthy naivety allows you to be separate from the internal language. Then you’re not bogged down by the technical terms and internal jargon.</p>
<p>Trying to explain things clearly to users can end up becoming too many words and terms you think they’ll understand. Internal company language can lead to unconsciously writing in a more formal tone. By being apart from that you can bring plain, simple language to the product.</p>
<h2>Show flaws in thinking</h2>
<p>It’s unfortunate, but some stakeholders may just not respect you and your role. They might not understand what you do, especially as it’s a relatively new industry. I’ve even had stakeholders dismiss me because of my young age. But I’ve used this against them.</p>
<p>One stakeholder had written a long list of options, things a user might own in their home. It was full of incorrect terms and out of date references. What particularly struck me was ‘palmtop’. What they were referring to was PDAs (Personal Digital Assistants) and similar handheld computers. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palmtop_PC" target="_blank">Palmtop computers first appeared in 1989.</a> And <a href="http://techland.time.com/2012/06/01/newton-reconsidered/" target="_blank">PDA was first used in 1992</a> (the year I was born).</p>
<p>So I feigned ignorance. I swallowed my pride and pretended to be naive, to show how silly the term ‘palmtop’ was. When we were discussing it, I simply said “What’s that? I’ve not heard of that before.” The stakeholder scoffed. But when they attempted to explain it, they soon realised it wasn’t something people used anymore — it wasn’t relevant.</p>
<p>So we then happily discussed other options. Things that were more relevant. They soon realised I could help them and discussing it in-person was much simpler. From then on, I had a great working relationship with that stakeholder.</p>
<h2>Be naive!</h2>
<p>I’m not suggesting this is the <i>only</i> tool in a UX writer’s toolkit. But it can be a really helpful one to have.</p>
<p>Overall, we have to be comfortable accepting what we don’t know. But we can use that lack of knowledge to our advantage. It can show up any flaws in thinking that happens within the status quo.</p>
<p>It’s also important to question everything. It’s the only way to build an understanding and learn these things. But it’s OK to keep your distance and not get too in-depth.</p>
<p>And always keep an open mind. UX writing isn’t about your preference, it’s about what works for users. So make sure you write plainly and simply. (Of course!)</p>

]]>
	</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Write-up of UX Brighton 2019</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/ux-brighton-19</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/ux-brighton-19</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
	<![CDATA[
	
<p>I’ve finally got myself to a UX Brighton conference! I’ve been to a couple of evening events, but it was great to get to the main event. It was a good way to get to know my new teammates more. And an opportunity to catch up with old contacts and friends.</p>
<p>There was a good variety of talks that were all interesting in their own way.</p>
<p>It was nice to see UX writing getting mentioned here and there. <a href="https://twitter.com/martynreding" target="_blank">Martyn Reding</a> discussed it in his talk, comparing “new practises” with historical examples. It was really great to see these comparisons brought forward. I particularly liked how earlier copywriting combined with design into creative teams. Much like what we want from UX writing now.</p>
<p>There were a couple of talks on voice design, which I found particularly interesting. Although, I would have liked more around designing the specific words and phrases. <a href="https://twitter.com/sappingtonemily" target="_blank">Emily Sappington</a> mentioned their healthcare voice ended communications with “Take care.” They had originally gone with “Hope you feel better soon!” in an overly happy tone. But this was seen as unhelpful and not always accurate (for obvious reasons!). So it was nice to hear how they considered this.</p>
<p>There were a few mentions, and a whole talk from <a href="https://twitter.com/doctorfine" target="_blank">Dr. Nick Fine</a>, about bringing science and “science thinking” into our practise. I really like this side of the conversation, so it was good to see it at the conference.</p>
<p>All in all it was a great event. It would be nice to see something similar happening for UX writing and content. Or maybe a future UX Brighton theme around it. There are so many connections and comparisons.</p>
<p>Like all these events, it’s nice to know we’re all having similar problems and challenges. But it’s probably worth us trying to open these events out to stakeholders. Then they hear these things first-hand and can the great speakers can help convince them.</p>
<img alt="My conference pass. It reads 'UX Brighton, Dominic Warren, Brandwatch'."src="/posts/images/ux-brighton-19.jpg"></img>

]]>
	</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Working hard or hardly working?</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/hardly-working</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/hardly-working</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
	<![CDATA[

<p>I've put up a <a href="/working-hard">new page full of photos</a>. They're all of me doing different work things, like workshops, presentations and sat at my desk at various workplaces. I found them when I was trawling through my photos and thought they belonged on the site.</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>

]]>
	</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Don’t be precious: accepting edits and feedback</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/accepting-feedback</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/accepting-feedback</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
	<![CDATA[

<p>With any writing, editing is an important part of the process - but also one of the most difficult parts. For UX design, there's a similar process. Getting stakeholders involved and ready to sign off on work involves a similar back-and-forth of feedback and changes. So when it comes to UX writing, it can be a challenging part of the job.</p>
<p>So, what techniques are there that can help us understand and accept feedback?</p>
<h2>Take a moment</h2>
<p>When you first get feedback, it's really easy to respond straight away with a knee-jerk reaction. Try not to.</p>
<p>Stop. Breathe. Think.</p>
<p>Once you've received the feedback, take a moment to take it in. Reflect on it. There's no rush. It feels weird at first, especially if you're in the room with the person giving feedback. But there's no harm in thinking things over. If you need to, tell the person giving the feedback you need time to take it away and reflect on it. They won't mind.</p>
<h2>Remember why feedback is important</h2>
<p>More often than not, you've asked for the feedback. So remember why you asked for it.</p>
<p>Writing, like any work, is never right first time. You can draft and redraft your work as often as you like. But it's not until someone looks at it with fresh eyes (they've never seen it before) that mistakes and inaccuracies become clear.</p>
<p>Ernest Hemingway is famously quoted as saying,</p>
<p class="quote">Write drunk. Edit sober.</p>
<p>While I don't recommend you get drunk, the idea stands true. Write freely, without restrictions. It's the best way to pull your thoughts and ideas out of your head. It helps you make sense of the often jumbled thought-processes. Then come back to it with your own fresh eyes and edit it. Part of that is also getting other people's thoughts - the best edits are those done collaboratively.</p>
<h2>Respond and analyse</h2>
<p>Part of getting feedback is also picking it apart to fully understand what the feedback means. So feel free to question the feedback. Ask for more clarity, present alternative scenarios, and delve deep.</p>
<p>The person giving the feedback will appreciate it and it'll make the changes even better.</p>
<h2>Learn to push back</h2>
<p>It's worth remembering, just because someone has provided feedback, it doesn't mean you have to do them. Collaborative working means working together. Not someone dictating changes to someone else. So if you have reason to disagree with a suggested change, let them know and explain why.</p>
<p>Any good UX writer relies on research and data. If you have evidence that the words you've written are understandable and human, then tell them. It doesn't have to be confrontational. The more people know the research, the better everyone's work will be.</p>
<h2>One last thing…</h2>
<p>Don't forget to be grateful. Remember that whoever gave you feedback took time out of their day to do so. No one comes to work to be mean and do bad work, so know they're trying to help you be better.</p>
<p>Accepting feedback is hard. It's a skill we have to develop over time. It's OK to admit that you're still learning - I still am. If you believe you have all the answers from the beginning, you'll struggle to get very far. It's through collaborative working and honest, open discussions that we can write our best copy. And this means our products will work better for our users too.</p>

]]>	
	</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>A late write-up of my ‘lunch and learn’ session at Clearleft</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/talking-at-clearleft</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/talking-at-clearleft</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
	<![CDATA[
	
<p>On the 14 June 2019, I spoke at <a href="https://clearleft.com/" target="_blank">Clearleft</a>, in Brighton. I was just there for an hour, doing a &apos;lunch and learn&apos; (or &apos;brown bag&apos;) session. But it was a really valuable experience.</p>
<p>Firstly, I really appreciated being invited. Clearleft is a company I&apos;ve followed since early in my career. As one of the leading UX agencies in Brighton, they do some excellent work. I&apos;m also privileged to be friends with some members of Clearleft — an added bonus!</p>
<p>I&apos;d only been at TrustedHousesitters for a little while at the time. So it was interesting to make the presentation and formulate my ideas and talking points. My talk was on: &apos;How a writer works within the design team&apos;.</p>
<p>It was really nice to talk about something more focused, talking about the projects I&apos;ve actually worked on. As opposed to the abstract general principles of UX writing. Everyone who attended seemed interested and there were lots of great questions. Some of them I had to take away to think over. But it was good to have the question and answer session to peel back the layers of what I&apos;d covered.</p>
<p>I hope everyone who attended found it useful and interesting. I certainly benefited from getting out of my comfort zone. Talking to a small audience was fun and I&apos;d definitely do it again.</p>
<img alt="A screenshot from Clearleft's Instagram story. Dominic sat in front of a screen showing the before and after of the redesigned TrustedHousesitters homepage." src="/posts/images/talking-at-clearleft-1.jpg"></img>
<img alt="Dominic sat in front of screen, talking about the different stages of the prototype." src="/posts/images/talking-at-clearleft-2.jpg"></img>

]]>
	</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Pulp and Jarvis Cocker list style guide</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/pulp-list-style-guide</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/pulp-list-style-guide</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
	<![CDATA[
	
<p>This is the style guide for my previous post, <a href="/posts/pulp-list">The Pulp and Jarvis Cocker list</a>.</p>
<p>The list is ordered by year, with the most recent at the top.</p>
<p>Italics are used for the names of books, albums, and films, eg <i>Notting Hill</i>.</p>
<p>Quotes are used for songs, eg “Red Right Hand”.</p>
<p>If unsure, see <a href="https://apvschicago.com/2011/04/titles-quote-marks-italics-underlining.html" target="_blank"><i>Chicago Manual of Style</i></a>.</p>
<p>Links should be at the beginning or end of the sentence.</p>
<p>Names should be written as their brand dictates, eg ‘JARV IS…’ is all capitals with ellipses at the end.</p>
<p>Year of release should be included next to album title in parenthesis, eg <i>Different Class</i> (1995).</p>

]]>
	</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Pulp and Jarvis Cocker list</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/pulp-list</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/pulp-list</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>A long list of links of everything to do with the band Pulp and Jarvis Cocker.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Giving up social media for a week</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/giving-up-social-media</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/giving-up-social-media</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
	<![CDATA[

<p>As someone who works in the digital tech, I’m conscious of the effect apps and social media can have on us. It’s been pretty well documented now and lots of news outlets have written about it.</p>
<p>Because of this, I like to think I have a pretty good relationship with my phone and social media. Certainly when I compare myself to friends and colleagues. And I feel I have enough understanding to know what’s happening when I am looking at them. However, I thought it would be a good test of myself to see if I could go without social media for a week. I’m particularly interested to see if my habits are worse than I realise.</p>
<p>I took inspiration from a few articles, but these stood out as fair, balanced accounts:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/six-weeks-100s-miles-hours-glorious-boredom-japan/" target="_blank">The Glorious, Almost-Disconnected Boredom Of My Walk In Japan</a> by Craig Mod, <i>Wired Magazine</i></li>
<li><a href="https://futurecrun.ch/articles/the-information-diet" target="_blank">The Information Diet</a> by Angus Hervey, <i>FutureCrunch</i></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/23/business/cell-phone-addiction.html" target="_blank">Do Not Disturb: How I Ditched My Phone And Unbroke My Brain</a> by Kevin Roose, <i>The New York Times</i></li>
</ul>
<h2>Preparation</h2>
<p>First, I deleted all my tweets. I didn’t need to do this, but what do I need them for? I thought it would give me a bit of a jolt and get me started. But it was pretty anticlimactic. I don’t miss them and I never spent time scrolling back over my own tweets anyway.</p>
<p>There were some really nice interactions with my peers, so it’s a little disappointing they’re gone. Although, I’m unlikely to look back on those. However, there are a couple of broken threads left, like one-sided conversations.</p>
<p>But, the main thing to do — I’ve deleted the Twitter and Instagram apps from my phone. I’ve also deleted the news app, so I don’t end up mindlessly scrolling through that, either.</p>
<p>Let’s go!</p>
<h2>Day 1: Tuesday 2 July</h2>
<p>It’s been a day without Twitter and Instagram on my phone. There’s been 3 occasions where I’ve grabbed my phone to look at those apps specifically. I’ve had a couple of moments where my chest has felt heavier . Maybe a desperation to see “what’s happening”? But after some thought I realised that I’m not missing anything.</p>
<p>I did stumble onto the Twitter website on my computer. I was trying to see if a celebrity had a website and went to their Twitter instead. I quickly closed it.</p>
<p>I spent 30 minutes of my evening reading my book, which was really relaxing.</p>
<p>Someone sent me a Whatsapp message which was an Instagram link. The temptation to just immediately click it without thinking almost overcame me at first. hat’s not necessarily a bad thing. But once I’m on Instagram, I know I would end up on the Search page, endlessly scrolling. I haven’t clicked it.</p>
<p>Also, I’ve signed up to a load of email newsletters — retro!</p>
<h2>Day 2: Wednesday 3 July</h2>
<p>I’m definitely feeling more motivated to do other things. Like reading my book yesterday. And writing again — this is the first article I’ve written in some time.</p>
<p>If I ever pick up my phone because I have a message I do find myself straying into the app menu and looking for Instagram. For a split second, I wonder where it is.</p>
<p>When I think of something I want to look up, like another writer or designer, my first instinct is to reach for my phone. I want to see if they’re on Instagram or Twitter — how do they use it? What sort of things do they post? It’s annoying when I catch myself. But it’ll be interesting to see if this happens less over the week.</p>
<p>Now, when I find myself without anything to do, I try to just sit or stand. I don’t find it boring. It’s nice to take in the surroundings and spot things you wouldn’t normally. Things like birds, or the trees, or new buildings and shops.</p>
<p>If I want something else to do, I’ve got a number of articles saved on my phone. These are all links from the different newsletters. It’s nice to read long form, even on my phone, and to feel I’m learning something.</p>
<p>I’ve found I’m noticing how much other people are looking at their phones too.</p>
<h2>Day 3: Thursday 4 July</h2>
<p>I’m getting more used to not grabbing my phone to scroll endlessly. I did go for it a couple times, but stopped myself before I even unlocked it. I’ve found it easier to concentrate on long form articles and my book, as well.</p>
<p>Weirdly, I’ve sent more messages to friends on Whatsapp — not sure if that’s related or not. I’ve also noticed that I’m spending less time looking at online shops. Perhaps materiality is linked to Instagram? Perhaps because you’re seeing celebrities and friends with their best things and experiences. Then that makes you jealous, FOMO (fear of missing out), or you just want to do it yourself.</p>
<p>As well as that, I’m developing a love for the email newsletter. I get the day’s news in the morning, which is nice (at the moment) and I don’t feel the need to check the news so much after that. I’m also reading articles on a variety of topics and learning new things because of it.</p>
<h2>Day 4: Friday 5 July</h2>
<p>Again, I’m noticing how much I don’t jump to look at my phone at any quiet moment. When I got home I got going around the house, rather than sitting on the sofa scrolling. Watching TV, I noticed I’m actually focusing on the show, rather than my eyes dropping to my phone. I’m particularly interested to see what happens over the weekend.</p>
<h2>Day 5: Saturday 6 July</h2>
<p>I feel, generally, I’m good at keeping off my phone over the weekend already. There’s usually enough chores or things to do to distract me from it. Even though I spent the first half of the day watching TV (I know, I know, but to be fair, it was season 3 of Stranger Things!) and didn’t look at my phone.</p>
<p>In the afternoon, while doing things in the garden I didn’t even have my phone on me. I’d left it upstairs, out of sight. This wasn’t a conscious action to avoid my phone. It was completely natural as I wasn’t even thinking about it.</p>
<h2>Day 6: Sunday 7 July</h2>
<p>There were a couple of times, just for a few minutes, where I thought ‘I wish I had something to look at’. It felt like an unnecessary punishment for myself. But I soon turned that around and took the opportunity to do nothing. To not look at my phone at all and just think. It felt good.</p>
<p>When I did need to search things on the fly I did it a lot quicker. Often, in the second it takes to open my phone, I’ve forgot what I want to search and opening Twitter. Now that isn’t the first thing to cross my mind.</p>
<h2>Day 7: Monday 8 July</h2>
<p>It’s definitely easier now. Looking at Instagram and Twitter is no longer the first thing I think of when I hold my phone. And that’s a habit I didn’t realise I had.</p>
<p>Now I feel I’m consuming much better quality content by email newsletters. It’s easier to read emails — I’m not jumping around to different messages like tweets. I can then delete them and move on. If I do ignore the notification and go into my inbox later, I don’t get trapped in endless scrolling. It’s more immediate, in a good way.</p>
<p>Even though it’s only been a week I definitely feel like I’ve already changed my habits. Also my relationship with online content and my phone is different. I thought I had a pretty good control on this, so at first it was hard to admit to myself. But it’s good to know I can improve this more.</p>
<p>Oh, and my battery lasted longer!</p>
<p>I’d really recommend trying this experiment if you want to. It definitely helps you assess your habits, even if you don’t want to change them.</p>

]]>
	</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>What is UX writing?</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/what-is-ux-writing</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/what-is-ux-writing</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>There are lots of articles about UX writing, what it is, and how it works. So I thought, why not add one more?</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>My new job resolutions</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/new-job-resolutions</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/new-job-resolutions</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>It’s the end of a very successful first week in my new role. Leading up to starting I was considering what new habits I want to form. As I progressed through the first week I’ve tried to trial some of these.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Goodbye RSA</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/goodbye-rsa</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/goodbye-rsa</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>After a year and a half, it’s time for me to say goodbye to RSA.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>How we read</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/how-we-read</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/how-we-read</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>Reading isn’t as simple as looking at words. Our bodies and brains do many things that let us understand what we see and how we store that information.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>every word matters: one year on</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/every-word-matters-one-year-on</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/every-word-matters-one-year-on</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>It's been a year to the day since I launched 'every word matters'.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>How workplace language dehumanises</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/how-workplace-language-dehumanises</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/how-workplace-language-dehumanises</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>As content designers and UX writers, we're specialists in language. But it's not just the words we read and write that are important. Spoken language is crucial to understanding our users' needs and what they do and don't understand.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>What Jurassic Park can teach us about too many stakeholders and past mistakes</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/jurassic-park-and-stakeholders</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/jurassic-park-and-stakeholders</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>Dealing with stakeholders is notoriously one of the hardest parts of working in Digital. There are conflicting priorities and agendas that Digital, when making a product or service, need to bring together into some kind of consensus.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Emotional content design</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/emotional-content-design</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/emotional-content-design</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 6 Dec 2017 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>It's repeated plenty of times, but we know that people don't read online like they would a printed page. So we have to be concise and as clear as possible. However, we also have to be human – and part of being human is emotion.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Why plain English isn’t ‘dumbing down’</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/plain-english-isnt-dumbing-down</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/plain-english-isnt-dumbing-down</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>Without an understanding of content and how users read on the web, it would be easy to just chuck all the information you know onto the page. But there's important reasons we use plain English and write the way we do.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Writing as design</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/writing-as-design</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/writing-as-design</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>There's continuing debate over whether everyone is a designer. The argument if this is true or not is still ongoing, but can writing be part of the design process? Is writing, itself, design?</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Writing about people</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/writing-about-people</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/writing-about-people</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>User experience design should always start with the user needs. However when we think of people as users we often forget they are, in fact, people.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sentence case or title case?</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/sentence-case-or-title-case</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/sentence-case-or-title-case</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>How we read on the web is becoming more and more understood. However, there’s long been an argument between using title case or sentence case.</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Writing for the web and content design</title>
<link>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/writing-for-the-web</link>
<guid>http://dominicwarren.com/posts/writing-for-the-web</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>Content Designers are enthusiastic about language and constantly talk about user needs and how we read on the web. But, what is content design?</description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>